<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Velatrix</title>
    <description>This blog focuses on the research aspects of tech industries by sharing informative articles and interviews with industry leaders.</description>
    <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 22:12:24 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 22:12:24 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Storytelling In Business</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In Jack and the beanstalk Jack and his mom own a cow, it was a nice cow but it was all they had, when Jack was out to sell their cow, instead of selling it for gold, he sells it for a handful of beans, beans that were supposed to be magical. For me that’s where the story ends. Yes, eventually Jack grows the beanstalk and robs the giant, gives all the stolen gold to his mom and then he kills the giant with the help of his ax. But all that stuff is irrelevant. The point is that he didn’t trade the cow for money or a sure thing, he traded the cow for a chance at something great. He trade it for opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Storytelling is a narrative that engages its listeners through psychological realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tales of stories mixed with education are not mere coincidence, stories are better understood than plain facts, they are easier to remember and are more encouraging to share. Jeremy Hsu in his article “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-secrets-of-storytelling/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The secret of storytelling&lt;/a&gt;” states that scientists are starting to agree that stories have a powerful and universal appeal that are tied to the neurological roots of our social cognition. But what is storytelling? It is a narrative that engages its listeners through psychological realism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is very much related to creative industries like cinematography, theatre and editorial activities. But is also among every task where creativity is involved. And if we acknowledge that creativity is involved in most professions and activities, then we can arrive at the conclusion that storytelling is part of most jobs out there. But as a business graduate I ask myself why didn’t I had a storytelling class during university. I would have appreciated more a storytelling class rather than ‘purchasing’..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity and business are as mixed as they can be. Great businesses didn’t start out of a ‘how-to’ business manual, but instead business people have always looked at new ways of doing things, always trying to come up with the next big idea, or new bold ways to resolve an existing problem. Business people without creativity are as useful as a typewriter is in todays digital world. (why this paragraph?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is a desired skill, yet not required, in education, in a job interview, in sales, in a executive position, etc. But the fact that is not required might confuse people in believing that they can be successful without it. But there are no successful professionals without good communication skills. And thats where storytelling comes in play, because storytelling is a potent persuasive tool that has the ability to shape beliefs and change minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are applying to university, looking for a new job, or simply trying to have better results doing what you do, try improving your storytelling skills. And every time you have to mention facts try communicating them in a more narrative way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/storytelling-in-business</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/storytelling-in-business</guid>
        
        <category>communication</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Design Thinking is a term that is often heard in academics environments, but its also what its behind products like the iPod and iPad. It is an iterative process for creating new and relevant solutions or new opportunities through a human-driven analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authors Christoph Meinel and Larry Leifer explain that there are 4 principles to design thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human rule: a design process is social.
The ambiguity rule: ambiguity is necessary.
The re-design rule: every design is re-design.
The tangibility rule: prototypes make ideas clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design thinking is usually related to ‘wicked problems’ or tricky problems, in which both the problem and the solution are unknown, incomplete or contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methods used in Design Thinking include observation, interviewing, creating ‘personas’, brainstorming, prototyping, and testing. Since this process is creative at its core, design thinking is often not fully understood in comparison with other more rational methods like analytical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One clear example of design thinking is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IDEO&lt;/a&gt;, a design and innovation company. IDEO takes a human-centered approach to work with their clients where design thinking is at its core. For Tim Brown, CEO of the company, design thinking in business is a competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The design thinking process can be based on 5 stages:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;EMPATHIZE:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathize consist of observing and engaging with the user. They are the ones that are going to benefit with your solution or opportunity, so its necessary to create empathy with them. The best solutions usually come from a great understanding of the human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;DEFINE:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the define stage a problem and a point of view is selected based on all the information gathered in the previous stage. This problem or challenge is going to lead the rest of the design thinking process, and it will be set along with a ‘persona’ or model user. The problem should be framed openly to create the opportunity for creative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;IDEATE:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the idea generation phase, where the brainstorming happens. The problem should be tackled from as many sides and perspectives as possible, there are not wrong or right ideas, so optimism should prevail. The more people participating the more ideas will be generated. It necessary not only to generate ideas from our own point of view but also thinking from the perspective of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PROTOTYPE:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototypes are often bypassed but they are as important as the ideas themselves. “If a picture is worth a thousand words, a prototype is worth a thousand meetings” is a classic IDEO quote. Since many prototypes might have to be produced, they should be made as cheaply and fastest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;TEST:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the stage where the solutions and the users come together, and all feedback is gathered.  Prototype as if you know you’re right, and test as if you know you’re wrong. Testing is the chance to refine the solutions and improve them. After the this stage iterate the whole process to come up with new findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/design-thinking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/design-thinking</guid>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Information Architecture?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;Finding is the new doing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Architecture has a fancy name and to many is a new and growing task in big organizations which work with a gazillion pieces of content like Google, Facebook, or Amazon.
But in reality the architecture of information is as old as information itself. It has always been part along with questions like “How do we structure this set of data so is easily found by others?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The index of a book is information architecture. Organizing books in a library by alphabetical order or by subject is information architecture. Imagine if 500 years ago the europeans that first arrived in the American continent, instead of making maps and using cartography, they had written directions and locations only using written words. It would have been terribly difficult if not impossible for others to arrive to the Americas. This example shows that Maps are another example of information architecture, which is structuring information so a person (or computer) can easily find what they are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words Information Architecture is the structure on how content is organized and presented to a user. Or as the Information Architecture Institute explains: “Information architecture is about helping people understand their surroundings and find what they’re looking for, in the real world as well as online.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the modern digital world Information Architecture is present in anything that contains information like websites, applications, softwares, intranets, etc. But who does it? Is there Information Architects out there? Information Architecture has rarely been a job title, though this has been changing in the last years with the appearance and growth of big web based information providers such as web browsers, social media companies, ecommerce platforms, online banks, and many other organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even though Information Architecture is fairly new as a job title, the task it is not, and has been shared by designers, developers, marketers, and anybody who has participated in the development of an information interface. People who call themselves Information Architects will have experience in all or some of following areas: design, marketing, content strategy, user experience, user interface, analytics, search optimization, business research, and other related tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Architecture uses research as its main tool and this can take the form of competitor analysis, reading academic papers on human/computer interaction, testing ideas on real users, analyzing existing industry and design standards, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, Martin Belam of the British newspaper “The Guardian” tells that they invited to their office some of the newspaper readers to try their new iPhone app. They filmed them to test whether they understood and made use of the functionality of the app that the newsgroup was developing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Architecture at a micro level can mean studying the categories to search a product on a eccomerce site. Or in a larger scale could be changing the general position of information in a site in accordance on how the target users are expected to find it. And in a strategic level might be deciding the brand experience that the user should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Architecture plays a major role on the delivering of content. If information cannot be found, that information is worthless. Information architecture help users and organizations in making information easily findable and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every service and product provided is based on information, and as every second there is more and more information created, finding the correct piece of content is becoming a harder task. The organizations that understand this the better are the ones that are going to adapt to the multi-connected and ultra-informed world that we are living in today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaspar Lobato Grinberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gasparg.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/what-is-information-architecture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/what-is-information-architecture</guid>
        
        <category>information architecture</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Still don&#39;t know what UX means?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been around the tech industry for the last years you have probably heard people talking about &lt;em&gt;UX design&lt;/em&gt;. And most of you may not know yet what this fancy acronym means. Don’t worry, its not rocket science, but it does can get very blurry at times. UX stands for User Experience Design and the best way to explain it is by first saying that UX is a series of well known tasks. Most organizations producing consumer products perform this tasks in a regular basis even without having a specialized UX designer. What I mean by this is that UX design can be part of the job of many people on an organization, like graphic designers, front-end developers, project managers, marketing professionals, business analysts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The User Experience Design tasks are:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Research:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Competitor Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Creating:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personas analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scenario analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wireframing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prototyping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing/Iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Execution and Analytics:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tracking Goals and Integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis and Iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great definition given by Sari Kujala on the Oxford Journal says that “The goal of user experience design in industry is to improve customer satisfaction and loyalty through the utility, ease of use, and pleasure provided in the interaction with a product.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main workflow of a UX designer starts by having a clear understanding of the product and the business goals, then to research the users and their decision processes. With all the data collected ‘personas patterns’ are built, which are the user behavior patterns that will help validate wireframes and workflows. Once the first prototypes are built the testing phase begins which is where the designs will be tested and evaluated continuously until the main stakeholder’s goals are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech industry in general is becoming more aware that UX plays a major role in the acquisition and retention of customers. If the experience of using your product doesn’t feel natural, straightforward or enhancing, then you’re leaving a window of opportunity for your competitors to take those customers away from you and never seeing them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;There’s no bad UX, there’s only better UX.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UX of the product you make is related and compared to all the other products in the environment where the user consumes them. Let me explain you, an user will compare the experience of using Amazon to the experience of using Facebook, even if Facebook is not a ecommerce platform, but because both are websites. The user will compare you to the experiences that he is related to, being these refined experiences or not, from your same industry or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Experience Design is never a completed job. The surroundings and environment of a user changes constantly, and these changes the user perception on what a good experience is. To exemplify this, search the image of the interface of Facebook of 2006 and compare it with today’s interface 10 years later, and you will see a dramatic example of how user experience changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of an organization in respect to User Experience Design should be to maintain a high level of usability and at the same time push the limits of what the user is already expecting from them. Don’t be reactive, be &lt;strong&gt;proactive&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/you-still-dont-know-what-ux-means</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/you-still-dont-know-what-ux-means</guid>
        
        <category>ux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tech Environment in Argentina</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people relates technology to Silicon Valley, as if they were synonyms, and for the most part they are right. Just by having a glance into the famous valley in California you would see only but technology and equity owners. This reality has started to create the general thought that if you want to work in the technology industries you’ve got no option but moving to the San Francisco Bay Area. And this general idea is wrong, there are other geographical options, many of them. Argentina is one, a country that has made a significant and increasing development of their technology industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Argentina’s policy on innovative industries like the creation of a network of tech companies for international promotion is helping many of these organization into jumping into foreign markets like the US. Other incentives of Argentina are the quality of graduates, the creativity, and the cooperation between academia and the business sector that encourages the development in the industry. In the other side inflation and an unstable currency market has been deterrents for Argentinian businesses and entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globant.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Globant&lt;/a&gt;’ is an example of a successful Argentinian technology company. In early 2000’s four friends decided on creating a software and IT company in Buenos Aires with the solely aim of having clients in the US and the UK. This led them first to the UK where they landed their first contract. Then they firmly entered the software industry by hacking the google wallet payment platform and gaining their respect. Today the almost 15 years old company from Argentina has an annual revenue of 200 million usd, more than 4700 employees, and 90% of its sales come from North America and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important player in the industry is ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hexacta.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hexacta&lt;/a&gt;’, which started working in 2000 with four people in a small office of Buenos Aires. They are a technology consulting and software development company. This company has overcome both national and international economic crises, a capability thats is usually shared by Argentinian companies since the country has had many instability times during its history. Hexacta today employees more than 400 professionals that work for clients all over the world, however its international revenue accounts only to a 50% of its total revenue, since its an active player nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A relatively new comer to the tech rodeo is the company ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://makingsense.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Making Sense&lt;/a&gt;’. Established in 2006 by two brothers, they offer software development services for other businesses but at the same time they have developed their own successful online marketing products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future for Argentinian tech companies seems bright from an international competitive point of view thanks to the once again working currency market and the growing international relationships of the government. However internally Argentina has to work to stay relevant about their workforce. Alex Robio, president and co-founder of Belatrix, a software development company states with respect to education in the country that “With the dynamic changes currently underway in the technology sector, education systems must actively change to ensure young people have the skills they need to enter the workforce.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/top-3-tech-companies-in-argentina</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/top-3-tech-companies-in-argentina</guid>
        
        <category>argentina</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>YAML front matter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;YAML front matter is perhaps the most important aspect of creating sites through Jekyll. It allows you to control how Jekyll processes and builds pages, create page-specific variables, and triggers file processing. Let’s take a closer look at front matter and how it can help you create more efficient Jekyll sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front matter must be the first item in a file and must take the form of valid YAML set between triple-dashed lines. Here is a basic example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;Welcome to Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;2015-08-15 12:34&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;James Williamson&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example Jekyll is instructed to use the &lt;strong&gt;default.html&lt;/strong&gt; template for the content, and page variables for both the &lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; of the page and the &lt;strong&gt;author&lt;/strong&gt; are created. These can be written to the page using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;page.title&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;page.author&lt;/code&gt; objects. A &lt;strong&gt;date&lt;/strong&gt; for the page is given as well, and when used for a Post this will override the date used in the name of the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many predefined Global variables that you can set in the front matter of a page or post. These are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;layout&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Specifies which template to use for the content. As such it must point to a file in the &lt;strong&gt;_layouts&lt;/strong&gt; directory. Do not add the file extension to the template name. To reference the &lt;strong&gt;post.html&lt;/strong&gt; template you would add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;layout: post&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;permalink&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Sets the permalink for the targeted file and is used to overwrite the default permalink style for a post. For example, the setting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;permalink: /blog/:title&lt;/code&gt; would overwrite the site permalink settings and locate the post at &lt;strong&gt;/blog/post-title/index.html&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;published&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;A boolean value that you can set to &lt;strong&gt;false&lt;/strong&gt; if you don’t want the post published as the site is generated.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;category&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;categories&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Assigns a single category or space-separated list of categories to a post. Categories can be used in permalinks and are hierarchical in nature. Allows you to structure posts like &lt;strong&gt;web-design/html/post-title/index.html&lt;/strong&gt;. Posts can also be organized and sorted by categories.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;tags&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Similar to categories, you can apply a single tag or multiples tags in a YAML list or a space-separated string. Although posts can be organized and sorted by tags, they can’t be used for permalinks like categories.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Custom variables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the predefined Global Variables, you can create any custom variable you want. That variable can then be accessed by any page or post that uses that content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common form of custom variable is to store information like page titles, author names, and descriptions that can be added to the page or in &lt;strong&gt;meta&lt;/strong&gt; tags to enhance page metadata. You can take this even further and control things like page layout as well. Let’s say that most pages in your site uses a simple sidebar, but occasionally you need to use a longer sidebar. In your template you could have the following markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-liquid&quot; data-lang=&quot;liquid&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;sidebar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sidebar-long&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;%}
    {% else %}
    {% include sidebar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kr&quot;&gt;endif&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in any page or post that uses this template all you would need to add is the following variable to the front matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sidebar-long: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining includes, templates, and front matter variables gives you an incredible amount of control over how pages are built, and limits the amount of variations you need in the form of templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even get to the point where you are generating entire pages with nothing but front matter. Let’s say you want to generate a single page for every tag that lists all posts tagged with that specific tag. You could create a template that generates everything dynamically based on the tag name. To create a new tag page, you simply name the file &lt;strong&gt;tag-name.md&lt;/strong&gt; and add the following to the front matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;tag-page&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;Tagged with Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;permalink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/tags/:title&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the file could be empty and Jekyll would dynamically generate the page based on the tag name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###SASS and CoffeeScript&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll provides built-in support for Sass and CoffeeScript, but won’t process those files automatically. To enable those files for processing, add an empty front matter region to the top of the page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The files will then be processed, and the resulting file will be located in the same directory in the generated site. The file &lt;strong&gt;css/layout.scss&lt;/strong&gt; would generate &lt;strong&gt;css/layout.css&lt;/strong&gt; in the finished site.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/front-matter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gasparlg.github.io/velatrix/velatrix/blog/front-matter</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>web design</category>
        
        <category>yaml</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
